Charles C. Carter

Information Technology and Data Analytics Professional

2315 Edgewood Road • Columbus, Georgia 31906 (706) 662-6351 • ccc31807@yahoo.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ccc31807 • https://github.com/ccc31807

ABOUT

Information technology and data analytics professional with wide experience in data analysis and reporting, systems administration, programming, database programming and development, software development, process automation, and instruction. Language proficiencies include C#, R, Python, and Perl. Database proficiencies include SQL Server, SQLite, PostgreSQL, and MySQL. Master of Science degrees in Applied Computer Science, Software Engineering, and Analytics (in progress). ABD in Software Engineering.

EDUCATION

Master of Science Candidate (grad Dec. 2021), Analytics Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, Georgia

Master of Science, Software Engineering Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama

Master of Science, Applied Computer Science Columbus State University, Columbus, Georgia

Bachelor of Arts, History Mercer University, Macon, Georgia

no degree, Mathematics

Columbus State University, Columbus, Georgia

EXPERIENCE

Instructor (full time)

January 2020 to current

Embry Riddle Aeronautical University, Marine Base Quantico, Virginia 22134

Instructor (full time)

May 2017 to December, 2019

Embry Riddle Aeronautical University, Fort Benning, Georgia 31905

- Instructor for the Microsoft Software and Systems Academy
- T-SQL, SQL Server, SQL fundamentals
- Programming in C#, program development and design
- ASP.NET, developing cloud applications
- Azure, Microsoft SQL Database, Azure application development

Instructor (adjunct)

August 2017 to current

Columbus State University, 4225 University Avenue, Columbus, Georgia, 31907

- Software Engineering
- Advanced Database

Quantitative Analyst

Dec 2014 to October, 2015

Synovus Bank, 33 West 11th Street, Columbus, Georgia 31901

- developed reproducible research automation with knitr and LATEX 2ε
- developed mapping applications with ggmap, choroplethr, and other R packages
- assisted in the development of automated data cleaning and rationalization procedures

• assisted in SDLC activities (SRS, BRD, FRD, and design documents)

Database Manager

Nov 2004 to Nov 2014

Troy University, 506 Manchester Expressway, Suite B20, Columbus, Georgia, 31904

- automated enrollment, registration, and term processes
- developed and maintained systems for reporting and analysis of academic data
- developed and administered databases supporting critical university functions
- implemented applications and programs as needed to support university needs

System administrator, developer

Jan 2001 to Dec 2013 (part time)

CFGroup, 2315 Edgewood Road, Columbus, Georgia, 31904

- administered HTTP (Apache) and database servers (MySQL)
- administered operating systems (SunOS and Linux)
- developed database driven web applications

Student, graduate assistant

May 2002 to May 2004

Columbus State University, 4225 University Avenue, Columbus, Georgia, 31907

- supervised student labs and tutored students
- administered Computer Science departmental servers (Linux, LinuxSE, FreeBSD)

Instructor

Jan 2000 to May 2002

Columbus Technical College, 928 Manchester Expressway, Columbus, Georgia, 31904

- taught Web Development curriculem (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, serverside development, database development, etc.)
- taught computer literacy, web development, and programming languages
- administered web servers for faculty and student web program (FreeBSD and Linux)

TECHNICAL CERTIFI-CATIONS

TSQL Querying (Exam # 70-761) Infomation Security Professional CNSS/NSA4011 UNIX/Linux System Administration Windows 2000 Network Administration Web Site Design Signal Officer Basic Course Microsoft Corporation Auburn University, Auburn, AL Dekalb Technical College, Decatur, GA Columbus Technical College, Columbus, GA Columbus Technical College, Columbus, GA U. S. Army Signal Corps, Fort Gordon, GA

TECHNICAL PROFICIEN-CIES

- Programming Languages: C#, Python, R, Octave, Perl, Common Lisp
- RDBMS: SQL Server, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Visualization Software: Tibco Spotfire
- Operating systems: Linux, Solaris, FreeBSD, Windows 2000
- Web Scripting Technologies: HTML, CSS, XML, XSLT, JavaScript
- Office Applications: Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, Outlook
- Other: Vim (vi), \LaTeX 2 ε , graphviz, dia, git & github

COMMUNITY SERVICE

- Columbus (Ga.) Data Science Meetup
- Taught programming courses for the Columbus home school association
- Tutored public school students in math
- Active in Gideons International
- Piper, Mercer University Pipes and Drums